news12.com 2018-05-10

# Privacy Policy

News 12 Interactive LLC (“News 12” or “we”), the owner and operator of the mobile application that linked you to this policy (the “app”), strives to offer users of mobile applications the many advantages of Internet and mobile technology and to provide an interactive and personalized experience on the app. We may use Personally Identifiable Information (your name, e-mail address, street address, telephone number or other information about you that could potentially identify you) subject to the terms of this privacy policy. Please note this policy applies only to information collected by News 12 through the app and does not impact information collected or used by News 12 or its Affiliates (defined below) through other means.

How we gather information from users.

How we collect and store information depends on your use of the app, the activities in which you elect to participate and the services provided. Most Personally Identifiable Information that we collect is what you tell us about yourself. For example, certain pages may prompt you to provide information, such as, to the extent applicable to the app, when you register for access to portions of the app, sign up for membership, submit a question or feedback, request certain features (e.g., newsletters, SMS alerts, news updates and other products), sign up for a subscription or make a purchase. You may also provide information when you participate in sweepstakes and contests, voting and polling activities, message boards and chat rooms and other interactive areas of the app, to the extent offered through the app. Like most apps, this app also collects information automatically and through the use of electronic tools that may be transparent to our visitors. For example, we may collect some information on device-level events, such as crashes, and associate that temporarily with your registration account in order to provide customer service. Most of the other information we collect, such as your device and hardware IDs and device type, the request type, your carrier, your carrier user ID, the content of your request, and basic usage statistics about your device and use of Newsday products and services, does not by itself identify you to Newsday. In addition, where portions of the app allow you to download and/or personalize the content you receive, we will record information about your downloads and preferences. Finally, if you use location-enabled products and services, you may be sending us location information.

Please note that we may collect location information when you visit our sites or use our applications, including location information either provided by a mobile device interacting with one of our sites or applications, or associated with your IP address, where we are permitted by law to process this information.

What we do with the information we collect.

We will use your information only as permitted by law and as set forth in this policy. Aggregated Information (information that does not personally identify you) may be used in many ways. As one example, we may combine information about your usage patterns with similar information obtained from other users to learn which pages are visited most or what features are most attractive. Aggregated Information may occasionally be shared with our advertisers and business partners, but cannot be used to contact you individually.

We also collect information to enhance your visit and deliver more individualized content and advertising. For example, we may use Personally Identifiable Information collected on the app to communicate with you regarding our Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy, products and services offered by News 12 and other News 12 Affiliates (defined below) and partners, administration of sweepstakes and contests, processing e-commerce transactions and other topics we think you might find of interest. In some cases we may combine Personally Identifiable Information collected on the app with demographic or other information (such as census records or customer information in our regular business records) to assist with tailoring advertising to your preferences and behaviors, and for other sales and marketing efforts of News 12 and its Affiliates. We reserve the right to share information with other News 12 business units and any entities that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with, News 12 (collectively, “Affiliates”), including without limitation News 12’s and its Affiliates’ newspapers, websites programming services and other platforms.

Personally Identifiable Information collected by News 12 may also be used for other purposes including but not limited to app administration and troubleshooting. Certain third parties who provide technical support for the operation of the app may access such information.

As we continue to develop our business, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. We may also preserve or disclose your information if required to do so by law, or in good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary for the following purposes: (1) to comply with legal process, such as a court order, search warrant, or subpoena; (2) to enforce the Terms of Service for this site; (3) to render service you request; (4) to protect the rights or property of News 12, and its third party suppliers and licensors; (5) in circumstances that we deem, in our sole discretion, to pose a threat to the safety of you or others; (6) to protect our rights; or (7) to collect on amounts you may owe us. Please note we may not provide you with notice prior to disclosure in such cases.

Your choice to opt out.

The quality news and information on the app is supported by advertising revenue and a controlled program of e-mail marketing is an important element of our online publishing business. Like other app publishers, we may permit our advertising and promotional partners to e-mail you about services, features, products, special offers and unique content we believe might interest you. If you prefer not to receive e-mail communications sent directly from our advertisers or promotional partners, you will be given an opportunity to decline before you provide us information we might use for this purpose. If you decline at the time you provide us such information, we will not share the Personally Identifiable Information you provide with non-Affiliate advertisers for such purposes, though we may on occasion send you information on their behalf.

E-mail marketing communications sent by News 12 to you will include a link allowing you to opt-out of future News 12 marketing communications (but does not include opt-out of newsletters). On the account management page of the site, if applicable, you can review and modify the list News 12 newsletters you have signed up to receive.

Please note that, in some situations (for example, submitting an entry to a contest or sweepstakes), permitting us to share your Personally Identifiable Information with a non-Affiliate advertiser or sponsor may be a required condition for you to take advantage of certain offers or services on the app. In such cases, we will advise you of this requirement in the terms and conditions of the specific offer or services (for example, the official rules of a contest or sweepstakes). Any permission granted to us by you in connection with your taking advantage of such offers or services to share your Personally Identifiable Information takes precedence over any ‘opt-out’ submitted by you pursuant to the preceding paragraph.

Affiliated sites, linked sites and advertisements.

News 12 expects its partners, advertisers and third-party Affiliates to respect the privacy of our users. However, third parties, including our partners, advertisers, Affiliates and other content providers accessible through the app, including social networking sites, may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. For example, during your visit to the app you may link to, or view as part of a frame on an app page, certain content that is actually created or hosted by a third party. Also, through the app you may be introduced to, or be able to access, information, websites, advertisements, features, contests or sweepstakes offered by other parties. News 12 is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing information on a feature or page operated by a third party.

While on our app, our advertisers, promotional partners or other third parties may use technology to attempt to identify some of your preferences or retrieve information about you. For example, some of our advertising may be served by third parties, such as ad networks. These ad networks may collect various non-identifying information, such as your mobile device type, device properties, IP address, video views, ad views, ad clicks, search queries, photo views, and page views, as well as the device identification code and/or the device MAC address. Ad networks may also combine all of this non-identifying information with other non-identifying information to infer interests or demographic characteristics. Ad networks may use this information to perform a variety of tasks, such as limiting the number of times a specific advertisement is presented to the same mobile device (frequency capping), providing an advertisement to only certain types of mobile devices, or providing a reports on the number of its advertisements that were clicked. Newsday does not control the use of this technology or the resulting information and is not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties.

Please be careful and responsible whenever you are online. Should you choose to voluntarily disclose Personally Identifiable Information on the app, such as in message boards, chat areas or in advertising or notices you post, that information can be viewed publicly and can be collected and used by third parties without our knowledge and may result in unsolicited messages from other individuals or third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of News 12 and this policy.

Children.

News 12 does not knowingly collect or solicit Personally Identifiable Information from or about children under 13 through the app except as permitted by law. If we discover we have received any information from a child under 13 through the app in violation of this policy, we will delete that information immediately. If you believe News 12 has any information from or about anyone under 13, please contact us at the address listed below.

Security of personal information

We have implemented commercially reasonable physical and electronic security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of your personal information. Despite our best efforts, however, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. To help us protect your privacy, you should maintain the secrecy of your email address and the password you may have set up in connection with your participation in the app.

Accessing and updating your personal information

To access, review, rectify, or delete your personal information that you have provided directly to us, please contact us via mail or e-mail at the addresses below. In addition, you may review and modify certain of your personal information through the account management page of the app, if applicable. While News 12 will make reasonable efforts to accommodate your request, we also reserve the right to impose certain restrictions and requirements on such access requests, if allowed or required by applicable laws.

California Privacy Rights

Beginning January 1, 2005, California law permits users of the app who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email or write to us at the contact information below.

Contacting us.

We can be reached by contacting:

News 12 Interactive LLC One Media Crossways

Woodbury, NY 11797 webmaster@news12.com

Changes to this policy.

News 12 reserves the right to change this policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes. Your continued use of the app following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. Information collected prior to the time any change is posted will be used according to the rules and laws that applied at the time the information was collected.

Consent to processing and transfer of information.

Governing law.

This policy and the use of the app are governed by New York law. Any claim related to the app or this policy shall be brought in a federal or state court in Nassau or Suffolk Counties, New York, within one year after the claim arises. You agree no such claim may be brought as a class action. Users of the app consent to the jurisdiction and venue of such court as the most convenient and appropriate for the resolution of disputes concerning this policy. The app is controlled, operated and administered entirely within the United States. If you are located outside the United States, please note the information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. You hereby consent to this transfer.

© 2016, News 12 Interactive LLC.

Version: February 2016
